

Christina Simmons

coderfoundry.com/christinasimmons

FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#
MVC
.NET
JavaScript
HTML5
CSS
ASP.NET
SQL
Bootstrap
JQuery
LINQ

AngularJS WebAPI

CODER

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284

(336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

EDUCATION

Western Carolina University,
Bachelor of Science in Criminal Justice and Emergency Management
Cullowhee, NC . 2006

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Coder Foundry, Web Software Engineer

Kernersville, NC · January 2016-June 2016

- Created a personal portfolio website using C#, MVC5 and JavaScript. Developed frontend using HTML5, Twitter Bootstrap and MVC model binding with Razor.
- Created a fully functional MVC bug tracker web application. Handled secure file upload functionality for approved file types. Database interaction done through LINQ to Entity framework.
- Created a fully functional car finder web application. Composed dynamic, responsive frontend design using AngularJS, HTML5 and Twitter Bootstrap. Accessed NHTSA's car recalls database using provided WebAPI to show car recalls.
- Created a fully functional financial portal web application using .NET MVC framework.
 Composed dynamic front-end design using partial views and AJAX.

Holly Springs Police Department, Telecommunicator / Dispatcher

Holly Springs, NC · May 2012–January 2016

- Worked with local, state and federal agencies managing multiple calls for service.
- Prioritized calls based on degree of urgency and either referred or resolved citizen issues.
- Trained new employees.

North Carolina State Highway Patrol, Patrol Telecommunicator

Raleigh, NC · December 2007-October 2010 & February 2011-May 2012

- Developed multitasking, prioritization and organizational skills while simultaneously working a multi-channel radio console, phones, NAWAS circuits, and DCI console.
- Worked closely with several coworkers assisting with tasks as needed, contributing to ease of work-flow and maintaining patrol standards.
- Maintained critical data for the State of North Carolina regarding absconders.

North Carolina Department of Corrections, Information Processing Technician

Raleigh, NC · November 2010-February 2011

- · Perform DCI functions.
- Enter, file, locate, validate and clear warrants.
- Maintain records on absconders, parolees, probationers and wanted subjects.
- Assist citizens and probation/parole officers.

City of Greensboro NC, Specialist 1 Emergency Comm

Greensboro, NC · May 2006-October 2006 & January 2007-August 2007

- Managed and updated critical data for first responders.
- Learned new program and taught pilot program to supervisors of first responders.